So now let's talk about Amazon MQ.
So we know about SQS and SNS
and they're cloud-native services
because they are proprietary protocols from AWS.
They use their own sets of APIs.
But if you are running traditional application on-premises,
you may use open protocols
such as MQTT, AMQP, STOMP, Openwire, WSS.
And when you're migrating your application to the cloud,
you may not want to re-engineer your application
to use the SQS and the SNS protocols or APIs.
So instead, you wanna use the traditional protocols
you used to, such as MQTT, AMQP, and so on.
So for this, we can use Amazon MQ.
So Amazon MQ is very simple.
It's a managed message broker service for two technologies,
for RabbitMQ and for ActiveMQ.
So RabbitMQ and ActiveMQ are, for example,
on-premises technologies that provide you access
to the open protocols I just mentioned.
So then we can get a managed version of these brokers
onto the cloud thanks to Amazon MQ.
So as such, you can understand the implications.
First of all, Amazon MQ doesn't scale as much as SQS or SNS,
which have sort of like infinite scaling.
And because Amazon MQ runs on servers,
you may have server issues.
And so you can run multi-AZ setup
with a failover if you want to be highly available.
Also, Amazon MQ comes with both a queue feature,
so it looks like SQS,
and topic features, it looks like SNS
as part of a single broker.
So Amazon MQ is going to be used only and only if
a company is migrating to the cloud
and needs to use one of these open protocols,
such as MQTT, AMQP, STOMP, et cetera, et cetera.
Otherwise, it should be using SQS and SNS
because they scale a lot better
and they're way more integrated
with Amazon Web Services than Amazon MQ.
So I hope that helps and I will see you in the next lecture.